Guide to the Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers, 1930s-2017 RL.11082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers
1930s-2017 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Matlock, Jack F.
RL.11082
210 Linear Feet
Jack Faust Matlock was US Ambassador to the Soviet Union from 1987-1991. This collection includes materials from him and his wife, photographer Rebecca Matlock, dating largely from the 1940s through the mid-2010s. The bulk of items relates to their work for the US Foreign Service; they were officially stationed in Washington, Moscow, Prague, Accra, Dar es Salaam, and Zanzibar and traveled extensively throughout the world. Jack Matlock was a key figure in the Ronald Reagan administration and participated in almost every US-USSR summit from the 1970s until his retirement in 1991. Also present in the collection are diaries, writings, memoranda, reports, clippings, interviews, photographs, event files, audiovisual materials, and other documents regarding the Matlocks' career, travels, interests, family life, and scholarship.
Arrangement
Grouped into series: Diaries, Foreign Service, Consecutive Files, Writings, Academia, Subjects, Personal, and Events. Audiovisual Materials are in a separate series but topically overlap with other series in the collection.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2016 to 2017.
Related Materials
See also the Rebecca Matlock Photographs, also held in the Rubenstein Library.
Collection Overview
This collection contains diaries, calendars, interviews, recordings, photographs, memoranda, clippings, writings, memorabilia, and other documents spanning the lives of Jack F. Matlock and Rebecca B. Matlock. The Matlocks spent 35 years in the US Foreign Service, with posts in Washington, Accra, Vienna, Germany, Zanzibar, Dar es Salaam, Moscow, and Prague. Their collection documents their government work as well as their family life, travels, and interactions with US and Soviet officials and citizens.
Materials have been sorted into series: Diaries, Foreign Service, Consecutive Files, Writings, Academia, Events, Subjects/Organizations/Names, and Personal Files. Each series is detailed below.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Viewing copies available; contact Research Services to coordinate access to viewing/use copies.
Biographical / Historical
Historical Note
Chronology
1928 Rebecca Burrum born, Manchester, Tennessee
1929 Oct. 1 Jack Matlock born, Greensboro, NC
1949 Jack Matlock marries Rebecca Burrum while they are undergraduates at Duke University
1950 Matlocks graduate with BAs from Duke University
1952 Jack Matlock graduates with MA from Columbia University
1953-1956 JM taught Russian literature and language at Dartmouth College
1956-1958 JM entered Foreign Service; worked as Research Analyst in Soviet Affairs, Washington DC.
1958-1960 Vice Consul and Third Secretary, American Embassy, Vienna
1960-1961 Language and training in Soviet affairs at US Army Advanced Russian Institute, Oberammergau, Federal Republic of Germany
1961-1963 Vice Consul and then Second Secretary, American Embassy, Moscow
1963-1966 Second Secretary, the First Secretary (Political Officer), American Embassy, Accra, Ghana
1967-1969 Consul and Principal Officer, Zanzibar
1969-1970 Deputy Chief of Mission, American Embassy, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania
1970-1971 Member of Senior Seminar on Foreign Policy, Dept. of State, Washington DC
1971-1974 Director of the Office of Soviet Union Affairs, Dept. of State, Washington DC
1974-1978 Deputy Chief of Mission, American Embassy, Moscow
1978-1979 Diplomat-in-Residence and visiting professor of political science, Vanderbilt University
1979-1980 Deputy Director, Foreign Service Institute, Dept. of State
1981 Jan.-Sept. Charge d'Affaires ad interim, American Embassy, Moscow
1981-1983 Ambassador to Czechoslovakia
1983-1986 Special Assistant to the President, Senior Director of European and Soviet Affairs on the National Security Council
1987-1991 Aug. Ambassador to the USSR, Moscow
1991 Aug.-Sept. Consultant, American Broadcasting Company (ABC)
1991-1993 Senior Research Scholar, Harriman Institute, Columbia University
1995 JM published Autopsy on an Empire: The American Ambassador's Account of the Collapse of the Soviet Union
1996-2001 George F. Kennan Professor, Institute for Advanced Study
2004 JM published Reagan and Gorbachev: How the Cold War Ended
2004 RM published At Spaso House: People and Meetings: Notes of the wife of an American ambassador (in Russian)
Cold War; United States. Embassy (Soviet Union); United States -- Foreign relations -- Soviet Union; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1981-1989; Audiovisual materials; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Russia -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Ambassadors -- American -- Soviet Union; United States. Foreign Service -- History; Ambassadors -- United States; Soviet Union; Zanzibar -- History; Spaso House (Moscow, Russia); Moscow (Russia) -- Photographs; United States -- Foreign policy; Russian literature; Russian language; Ambassadors' spouses; Matlock, Rebecca B., 1928-; Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeevich, 1931-; Shevardnadze, Ė. A. (Ėduard Amvrosievich), 1928-2014; Reagan, Ronald; Bush, George, 1924-2018; United States. Dept. of State; Matlock family; Sakharov, Andreĭ, 1921-1989; Baker, James Addison, 1930-; Shultz, George Pratt, 1920-; United States. Foreign Service; United World Federalists (U.S.); Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae; National Security Council (U.S.); Leskov, N. S. (Nikolai Semenovich), 1831-1895; USSR-USA Summit
- Diaries and Calendars, 1946-2015; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Jack Matlock's journals, diaries, appointment books, and notes, with the bulk of materials dating from the mid-1980s through his retirement from the Foreign Service in 1991. Matlock's private accounts of his activities during the later years of his foreign service career were thorough and prolific. He embraced personal computing and developed his own Cyrillic font in LaTex to allow for journaling in Russian and English. This series contains printouts of his personal diaries kept during his work for Reagan's White House and as Ambassador to the USSR.
  Matlock used his diaries as reference points for later writings and reviews of his own career, and subsequently added and edited his own entries to include newly revealed insights or information. This series includes Matlock's bound journals with handwritten entries, his "original" typed diaries (as printed out in the 1980s), edited and supplemented diaries (which appear to have been printed at a later point) that include Matlock's inserted notes, research, annotations, corrections, and other related information. There is also a set of declassified memoranda and other FOIA'd materials, as well as collected published materials, which allowed Matlock to cross-reference events he experienced with other coverage or perspectives.
  The series also contains a variety of appointment books and calendars, some more detailed and some lightly used. The spiral notebooks and loose notes, arranged chronologically, overlap with Matlock's notes located throughout the Foreign Service Series - some in standalone folders and some filed with specific events or topics. This sorting reflects the original arrangement of the papers at the time of acquisition by Rubenstein Library.
  - JM Typed Diaries, 1983-1986; 1
    - Typed (and handwritten) diary, 1983; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Typed diary, 1984 Jan.-Mar. (Box 1)
      includes handwritten edits
    - Typed diary, 1984 Apr.-May (Box 1)
    - Typed diary, 1984 June (Box 1)
    - Typed diary, 1984 July (Box 1)
    - Typed diary, 1984 Aug.-Sept. (Box 1)
    - Typed diary, 1986 Jan., Nov. (Box 1)
      loose pages
    - Typed diary, 1986 Nov. 4-Dec. 31 (Box 113)
  - JM Typed Diaries with edits and annotations, 1983-1991; 2
    - Edited diary, 1983 Dec.-1984 Jan. (Box 1)
    - Edited diary, 1984 Jan.-Feb. (Box 1)
    - Edited diary, 1984 Jan.-Apr. (Box 1)
      later printing; unclear if typed annotations included
    - Edited diary, 1984 May-June (Box 1)
    - Edited diary, 1984 July-Aug. (Box 1)
      includes annotations, notes
    - Edited diary, 1984 Sept.-Nov. (Box 1)
      includes annotations, references to notepads, handwritten notes. 1984 memo pad included.
    - Edited diary, 1984 Sept.-Dec. (Box 1)
      later printing; with inserted transcripts and annotations.
    - Edited diary, 1987 July-Sept. (Box 1)
      with annotations, comments, etc.
    - Edited diary, 1987 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1)
      with inserted documents, annotations, comments, etc.
    - Edited diary, 1988 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2)
      includes comments, annotations, inserted entries
    - Edited diary, 1988 Apr.-June (Box 2)
      includes comments, annotations, edits
    - Edited diary, 1988 July-Sept. (Box 2)
      includes commentary, some annotations and edits
    - Edited diary, 1988 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2)
      largely blank, with some annotations and comments
    - Edited diary, 1989 (Box 2)
      with inserted notes, entries, and correspondence
    - Edited diary, 1990 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2)
      includes annotations, edits, and loose pages
    - Edited diary, 1990 Apr.-June (Box 2)
      with corrections, edits
    - Edited diary, 1990 Jan.-May; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Edited diary, 1990 June-Aug. (Box 2)
      with edits, corrections, annotations, some laid in notes
    - Edited diary, 1990 Sept.-Dec.; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Edited diary, 1991 June-Sept. (Box 2)
      later printing; with typed comments, notes, annotations
    - Edited diary, 1991 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2)
    - Edited diary pages, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
      Mixed years with annotations re: photographs, other notes. Probably duplicative of earlier years, but extends into 1992.
  - JM Supplemented Diaries, 1985-1992; 3
    - Supplemented diary, 1985; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Supplemented diary, 1986; 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Supplemented diary, 1986 Jan.-Aug.; 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Supplemented diary, 1987; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Supplemented diary, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Supplemented diary excerpts, 1992 Mar., Sept. (Box 113)
  - JM Handwritten bound journals and diaries, 1946, 1982-2001; 7
    - JM travel diary re: trip to Washington DC, 1946 July 25-28 (Box 113)
    - Bound journal, 1982 (Box 8)
      with laid in pages
    - BJB-83-A, 1983 May-Sept. (Box 9)
      with laid in notes
    - BJB-83-B and BJB-84-A, 1983 Sept.-1984 Feb. (Box 9)
      with laid in entries and notes
    - BJB-84-B, 1984 Feb.-Sept. (Box 9)
    - BJB-84-C and BJB-85-A, 1984 Sept.-1985 May (Box 9)
    - BJB-85-B, 1985 May-Oct. (Box 9)
      with laid in entries, notes, and program invitation
    - BJB-85-C and BJB-86-A, 1985 Dec.-1986 May (Box 9)
      "Daily notes"
    - BJB-86-B, 1986 May-Nov. (Box 9)
      with laid in clipping, notes, entries
    - BJB-86-C, 1986 Nov.-1987 Dec., 1988 (Box 9)
      with laid in entries and notes, incomplete
    - BJB-88-A, 1988 Jan.-Mar. (Box 9)
      with laid in letter, notes
    - BJB-88-B, 1988 Apr.-Dec. (Box 9)
      with report re: START, notes
    - BJB-88-C, 1988 July-Sept. (Box 10)
    - BJB-88-D, 1988 Oct.-Dec. (Box 10)
      inserted notes, invitation
    - BJB-89-A, 1989 Jan.-Mar. (Box 10)
    - BJB-89-B, 1989 Apr.-June (Box 10)
    - BJB-89-C, 1989 July-Sept. (Box 10)
      with laid in notes, receipts
    - BJB-89-D, 1989 Oct.-Dec. (Box 10)
      with inserted pages
    - BJB-90-A, 1990 Jan.-Mar. (Box 10)
      with inserted notes
    - BJB-90-B, 1990 Apr.-June (Box 10)
      with laid in schedule, June 1990
    - BJB-90-C, 1990 July-Sept. (Box 10)
    - BJB-90-D, 1990 Oct.-Dec. (Box 10)
    - BJB-91-A, 1991 Jan.-Mar. (Box 11)
    - BJB-91-B, 1991 Apr.-June (Box 11)
      with laid in post-its, notes
    - BJB-91-C, 1991 July-Sept. (Box 11)
      inserted program, Oct. 1991
    - BJB-91-D, 1991 Oct.-Dec. (Box 11)
      with laid in pages, notes
    - BJB-87-AA, 88-AA, 89-AA, 1987 Aug.-1989 Sept. (Box 11)
      "Meeting notes"
    - BJB-89-BB, 90-AA, 1989 Oct.-1990 May (Box 11)
    - Bound journal, 1994 Jan.-Mar. (Box 11)
    - Bound journal, 1994 Apr.-July (Box 11)
      with laid in notes, agenda
    - Bound journal, 1997 Jan.-Mar. (Box 11)
    - Bound journal, 1998 (Box 11)
      with laid in notes, schedule
    - Bound journal, 1997-2000 (Box 11)
      from Princeton/IAS years, with entries inserted
    - Bound journal: travel notes, 2000-2001 (Box 12)
      Including Moscow, Baltic Sea cruise, Boston, Princeton
    - Bound journal: travel notes, 1999, 2001 (Box 12)
      Including Gorbachev talk in Cambridge; Antarctica
  - JM Spiral notebooks, handwritten, 1970s, 1984-2000s; 4
    Contains some prose, but largely these notebooks consist of to-dos and other relatively miscellaneous entries created in the course of routine activities by JM. These are seen as descrete from the journals subseries, which have more formally crafted entries by Matlock.
    - Spiral notebooks, 1984 Sept. (Box 3)
      2 notepads
    - Spiral notebooks, 1984 Jan.-1985 May (Box 3)
      numbers 1-3
    - Spiral notebooks, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      numbers 4-6
    - Spiral notebooks, 1985 Nov. (Box 3)
      numbers 8-9
    - Spiral notebooks, 1986 (Box 3)
      numbers 10-12
    - Spiral notebooks, 1986 (Box 4)
      number 14, 1 unnumbered
    - Spiral notebooks, 1987 May-June (Box 4)
      1 notepad
    - Spiral notebooks, 1993-2003 (Box 4)
      5 booklets
    - Disbound notebook pages, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
    - Spiral notebooks, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
      3 booklets (numbers 1-3)
    - JM notebook, with travel notes re: South Africa, Japan, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 113)
    - Notebooks re: Autopsy, other to-dos, 1992 and undated (Box 113)
    - Memo books (3 total), including auto record book, 1970s, 1979 (Box 113)
    - Notebooks with assorted entries, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Notebooks, 2001-2008, 2011 and undated; 8 folders (Box 113)
  - Reference materials, 1981-1990; 5
    - Declassified and collected documents, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Declassified and collected documents, 1982; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Declassified and collected documents, 1984-1991 (Box 4)
      Includes clippings, memorandum, copies, assembled by JM
    - Declassified and collected documents, 1988-1991; 2 folders (Box 4)
      Bulk from 1989. Includes original memoranda, photocopies of JM notes.
    - Collected documents binder, 1992 (Box 4)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, etc.
    - Chronological reference binder, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Chronological reference binder, 1990; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - JM Appointment books, 1965-1996; 6
    - Appointment book, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Appointment book, 1966 (Box 4)
      with 2 laid in photographs
    - Appointment books, 1967; 3 folders (Box 5)
      2 volumes; with laid in notes, correspondence, schedules
    - Appointment books, 1968; 3 folders (Box 5)
      2 volumes; with laid in notes, invitations, schedules
    - Appointment book, 1969; 2 folders (Box 5)
      with laid in clippings, notes, correspondence
    - Appointment book, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Appointment book, 1972; 2 folders (Box 5)
      with laid in agendas, notes, correspondence
    - Appointment book, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Appointment book, 1974; 1 of 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Appointment book, 1974; 2 of 2 folders (Box 6)
      with laid in agendas, schedules, notes
    - Appointment book, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Appointment book, 1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
      with laid in agendas, notes
    - Appointment book, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Appointment books, 1978 (Box 6)
      2 books. Blue with laid in agendas, notes, correspondence, invitations. Green likely belongs to RM.
    - Appointment book, 1979; 2 folders (Box 6)
      with laid in notes, agendas, correspondence
    - Appointment book, 1979 July-Dec. (Box 6)
    - Appointment book, 1980 (Box 6)
      with laid in schedules, notes, invitations
    - Appointment book, 1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
      with laid in schedules, notes
    - Appointment book, 1982 (Box 6)
      with laid in photocopy
    - Appointment book, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Appointment book, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Appointment book, 1985 (Box 7)
      with laid in clipping
    - Appointment book, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Appointment book, 1987; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Appointment book, 1988; 4 folders (Box 7)
      2 volumes, with reference inserts
    - Appointment book, 1989; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Appointment book, 1990; 3 folders (Box 8)
      2 volumes, one with laid in memo
    - Appointment book, 1991; 2 folders (Box 8)
      2 volumes; one is Jan.-May only
    - Appointment book, 1992; 2 folders (Box 8)
      with laid in notes, schedules
    - Appointment book, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Appointment book, 1994; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Appointment book, 1995; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Appointment book, 1996 Jan.-Sept. (Box 8)
    - Appointment calendar pages, 1992-1994 (Box 113)
    - Appointment calendars, loose pages; includes commitments and schedules, 1996-2000 (Box 113)
    - Appointment calendar pages, 2006-2007; 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Appointment book, 2010 (Box 113)
  - JM Notepads and notes, 1987-1991; 8
    - VN-87-04, 1987 April; 2 folders (Box 12)
      10 notepads
    - VN-87-06, 08, 1987 June, Aug. (Box 12)
      4 notepads, loose pages
    - Notepad, 1987 Oct. (Box 12)
    - Notepads and notes, 1988 Mar., April; 2 folders (Box 12)
      6 notepads, loose pages, clippings (VN-88-03, 04)
    - VN-88-05, 06, 1988 May, June (Box 12)
      5 notepads
    - Notes, 1988 (Box 12)
      "Miscellaneous" notes and memos
    - Notes, 1987-1989 (Box 12)
      Meeting notes, loose notes
    - Notepads and notes, 1989; 3 folders (Box 12)
      Notepads, meeting notes, cables, memos
    - BAM-1989 (Box 12)
      Loose datebook pages
    - BAM-1990 (Box 12)
    - Notepads and notes, 1990; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Notepads and notes, 1991 Apr. (Box 12)
    - Notepad, 1990 or 1991 (Box 12)
      Re: Yeltsin meeting
    - BN-87, 88A, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
      bound notebook
    - BN-88B, 1988 (Box 12)
    - BN-90, 91A, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
    - BN-91B, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Loose notes, approximately 1993 (Box 113)
    - Loose notes and to-dos, 1995-1996; 3 folders (Box 113)
    - Loose notes, approximately 2000 (Box 113)
    - Loose notes, 2011, undated; 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Datebooks and card files, 9
    - Datebook, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1970 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1979 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1980 (Box 13)
    - Datebook, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Index cards, 1986 Aug. (Box 13)
      with schedules, notes for events
    - Monthly datebooks, 1986 Oct.-1989 June (Box 13)
      Spiral pocket calendars, arranged by month
    - Monthly datebooks, 1989 July-1991 Nov. (Box 14)
    - Datebook, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 1994 (Box 14)
      Biannual pocket calendars
    - Datebook, 1995 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 1996 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 1998 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 1999 (Box 14)
    - Datebooks, 2000 (Box 15)
    - Datebook, 2000-2001 (Box 15)
    - Datebooks, 2001 (Box 15)
    - Datebooks, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Datebooks, 2003 (Box 15)
    - Datebooks, 2006-2009 (Box 15)
      Annual pocket calendars
    - Index cards, 1970s (Box 15)
      Russian vocabulary and notes
    - Index cards for JM's notes on the Union of Soviet Writers, 1955-1970s? (Box 16)
      Appears related to JM's research and notes for his first dissertation or for his early work for the State Dept. Notes regarding writers and works up through 1954.
    - Index cards with notes for learning Russian and an unidentified bibliography, 1950s, undated (Box 17)
- Foreign Service, 1950-1991
  This series contains materials created and acquired during Jack Matlock's career as a foreign service officer for the U.S. Dept. of State (1956-1981), his appointments as ambassador to Czechoslovakia (1981-1983) and the Soviet Union (1987-1991), and his work for the National Security Council and the White House (1983-1987). Materials are grouped by phases of Matlock's career, and are largely arranged chronologically and then by format. Rebecca Matlock's official duties and personal activities, especially as wife to the US Ambassador, is also well documented in this series. The series contains general and personal correspondence, government memoranda, invitations, schedules and programs, official itineraries and logistics, cables received, clippings and reports collected, specific event files for substantial activities at the embassy, and other administrative and topical information relating to the operations of the embassies in Accra, Dar es Salaam, Prague, and Moscow during the Matlocks' career. There is also significant material from Matlock's home leave, travels and work in the United States, and his academic appointment as Diplomat-in-Residence at Vanderbilt University in 1979-1980.
  - Early career, 1950-1971
    Jack Matlock initially began working for the State Department while studying and pursuing his doctorate in Russian literature. Early materials include his applications and correspondence regarding his background checks, as well as early research files from his projects on the Index to Stalin's Works and his first dissertation on the Union of Soviet Writers. Research files overlap between the Academia and Foreign Service series. Once hired fulltime by the State Dept., Matlock created reports and collected materials on Soviet internal affairs, writing intelligence briefs on specific publications and activities in the Soviet Union.
    The subseries includes his travels and various assignments in Germany, Moscow, and Vienna, and then his transfer to Ghana and later Zanzibar and Dar es Salaam. By this point they had five children; the official Foreign Service series overlaps with the Personal Series documenting the family's activities and children's education during this period. The Matlocks left Tanzania in 1970 and returned for Jack to work as a scholar at the Senior Seminar in the Foreign Service Institute; his research on Japan and the Soviet Union is also present in this subseries. Files are largely arranged chronologically with a group of correspondence collected for the period 1950-1971.
    - Soviet literature research, 1950s (Box 36)
      Clippings, drafts, notes by JM
    - Soviet underground poetry, 1940s-1960s (Box 36)
    - Stalin's Works indexing correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 36)
      Includes correspondence with Fred Holling
    - Stalin's Works draft reports, indices, notes, 1950s; 5 folders (Box 60)
    - JM applications for studies, fellowships, employment, 1950-1956 (Box 36)
    - Foreign Service application and hiring materials, 1956-1960 (Box 36)
      Includes exam materials, correspondence, background checks, salary, appointments
    - Union of Soviet Writers research, report, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 36)
      JM report draft, clippings re: USW
    - Soviet Preliminary Screening Committee materials, 1954-1956 (Box 36)
      Correspondence re: Ford Foundation Foreign Study and Research Fellowship program
    - Ford Foundation Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program, 1957-1958 (Box 36)
      Bibliographies of publications by fellows
    - Collected research, reports re: world affairs, foreign service, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet Union: Government, law, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet culture, general, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet economy, industry, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet Union: foreign policy, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet Union: sociology, 1950s (Box 36)
    - JM research files: Soviet Union: Communist Party, 1950s (Box 36)